<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>writeup - Tag - Frost's blog</title><link>/tags/writeup/</link><description>writeup - Tag - Frost's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 11:28:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/writeup/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Sekai CTF 2023] Conquest of Camelot writeup</title><link>/posts/sekai2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 11:28:00 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/sekai2023/</guid><description>Conquest of Camelot Given file camelot Description Unlock the secrets and unearth Camelot&amp;rsquo;s grail hidden within.
Author: sahuang
Basic analysis We are given a 64-bit ELF binary, and according to the challenge page, it&amp;rsquo;s written in OCaml. Throwing the binary to IDA and searching for the prompted string, we can locate the main logic of the program at camlDune__exe__Camelot__entry.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked with (or heard about) Ocaml before, so the binary threw me off a little bit.</description></item><item><title>[TSJ CTF 2022] javascript_vm, w4nn4cryp7 writeup</title><link>/posts/tsjctf2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 16:43:50 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/tsjctf2022/</guid><description>This is another CTF that I get to play with the people at team Project Sekai. The challenges are nice and interesting, and here are my writeups for the 2 RE challenges that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to solve.
javascript_vm Given file chall.bin
VM source
Description There are two kinds of Javascript virtual machines. Those who understand Javascript (like node.js) and those who don&amp;rsquo;t (like &amp;hellip; ?).
Author: @wxrdnx
Writing a disassembler This is a classic vm chall.</description></item><item><title>[AllesCTF2021] Monstrosity writeup</title><link>/posts/allesctf_2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:08:06 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/allesctf_2021/</guid><description>Writeup for AllesCTF 2021</description></item><item><title>[redpwnCTF2021] pickled-onions, 2k writeups</title><link>/posts/redpwn2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:54:37 +0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/redpwn2021/</guid><description>Writeup for redpwnCTF 2021</description></item><item><title>Rootme challenge - SEHVEH</title><link>/posts/old_posts/2020-09-11-sehveh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/old_posts/2020-09-11-sehveh/</guid><description>Kể ra thì từ khi tạo blog đến giờ mình chưa viết được bài nào ra hồn cả. Mấy tuần trước mình đã có dự định là sau khi thi xong sẽ bắt đầu việc viết lách, thế nhưng rốt cục bệnh lười lại tái phát. Mãi đến hôm nay, sau một hồi đấu tranh với cái tính nhác việc, mình mới chịu mở lap lên và ngồi lọc cọc gõ ra bài này.</description></item><item><title>A week with Angstromctf 2020</title><link>/posts/old_posts/2020-07-07-angstrom-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/old_posts/2020-07-07-angstrom-2020/</guid><description>So this post’s gonna be in English. Why? I don’t know, just feel like writing in English 🙂
I spent the whole week doing nothing but solving the RE challenges from Angstromctf (so far, I only managed to solve half of them, the easy half, that is). So I figured I should write a little bit about those challenges and what I’ve learned trying to solve them. Ok, here we go.</description></item><item><title>Angr_CTF</title><link>/posts/old_posts/2020-07-07-angr-ctf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>/posts/old_posts/2020-07-07-angr-ctf/</guid><description>Đây là post ghi lại lời giải của những bài mình giải được trong Angr_CTF: https://github.com/jakespringer/angr_ctf. Ok, bắt đầu luôn nào.
Note: Bài này ở wordpress thì mình ghi khá chi tiết, tuy nhiên khi dời qua đây thì bệnh lười lại tái phát. Do đó mình sẽ không ghi lại đầy đủ mà chỉ viết những điểm chính thôi (thêm nữa là không có hình chụp IDA luôn nha). Để đọc bài viết chi tiết thì bạn có thể vào đây</description></item></channel></rss>